RATHIN JEYARAM

■ EMAIL | in LINKEDIN | 66 PUBLICATIONS | 67 GITHUB

PhD student studying Social Networks and Team Organisation in Science. Passionate to translate my interests in Networks, Computational Social Science and skills in data analysis to tackle core R&D challenges. Particularly interested in facilitating transformation driven by research and integrating, analysing data from multiple stakeholders.

EXPERIENCE

01/2023-05/2023	Visiting PhD Student School of Public Policy, Georgia Institute of Technology Semester exchange working on my doctoral thesis project
09/2020-09/2021	Research Engineer Centre for Research and Interdisciplinarity (CRI), Paris Projects in Team Science and Collaborative Learning focusing on how social interactions drive adaptation and peer-learning mechanisms
12/2019-08/2020	Research Intern Centre for Research and Interdisciplinarity (CRI), Paris Understanding how team interactions drive performance through the analysis of a large-scale dataset of SynBio teams.
05/2019-07/2019	Summer Research Intern University of Toronto at Scarborough Network Science and Data driven analysis to predict extracellular receptor function in Arabidopsis thaliana.
05/2018–11/2018	Visiting Student Researcher National University of Singapore Studied evolutionary phylogenetic networks from the perspective of graph theory and algorithm design.

EDUCATION

10/2021–Present	DOCTORATE - MATHEMATIQUES ET SCIENCES INFORMATIQUES Title: Team Organisation and Learning in Open Innovation Frontieres of Innovation in Research and Education (FIRE) - ED474 Université Paris Cité, France
06/2015-08/2020	INTEGRATED M.Sc IN THEORETICAL COMPUTER SCIENCE PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore, India Grade: 9.19/10 Activities and Societies: EDITORIAL TEAM: CAP and Nature Club (2016-18) QUALITY ASSURANCE TEAM: Department Events Board (2017-19)

INTERESTS

- PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS: Data Science, Network Analysis and Computational Social Science to tackle multi-stakeholder challenges.
- RELEVANT COURSEWORK: Network Science, Social Network Analysis, Data Science, Machine Learning, Statistics, Data Visualization, Algorithms and Complexity, Mathematical Modeling, Graph Theory

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING: R for Data Science, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualisation, Modelling

Python for Data Analysis, Algorithms, LLMs and ML libraries PROGRAMMING:

MSOffice. GSuite Tools:

Communication, Collaboration, Problem Solving, Adaptability TRANSVERSAL: LANGUAGES: Tamil (Native), English (Bilingual), French (Limited Working)

CURRENT PROJECTS

- Team Organisation and Learning in Open Innovation: Doctoral thesis work studying teams in science and engineering. My objectives are to describe measures of division of labour, collaboration, task organisation and identify which dimensions do teams adapt as they learn over time.
- · Reconstructing Social Networks from Free-Text using Large Language Models: The aim of this work is to build a pipeline for reconstructing and validating networks of user-activity relationships from self-reported attribution statements of scientific teams.
- Quantifying Peer Influence in Collaborative Learning: Using mobile communication data to understand peer influence in learning and quantifying its effect on group and individual performance in a collaborative setting.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Student Mentor, Home Association 10/2021-PRESENT

> Designing educational curriculum and organising project-based learning programs to facilitate students to address local challenges around the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).

Programs held in Senegal and Rwanda.

03/2020-12/2020 Data Analyst, The OpenCovid19 Initiative

> Data-driven analysis of communication between projects and stakeholders within the initiative to identify the processes that underlie user activity and facilitate member

engagement.